Register to The Henry Gilbert Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Music by Others, 1843-1917; Series II; 3.75' (9 boxes)
  - Music by Others: Miscellaneous Works, II.D
    - I know that my Redeemer liveth. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, no date., Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759 (Box 24, Folder 140)
    - Let thine hand help me / arranged by Geo. Wm. Warren. - New York: William A. Pond, c1869., Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759 (Box 24, Folder 140)
    - The Messiah: in vocal score / arranged by Vincent Novello. - London: London Sacred Music Warehouse, no date., Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759 (Box 24, Folder 140)
    - Boston Handel and Haydn Society Collection of Church music... - Boston: Richardson and Lord, 1828., Handel and Haydn Society (Box 24, Folder 141)
    - Absence: a four part-song. London: Novello, Ewer and Company, no date, Hatton, John L. (Box 24, Folder 142)
    - Come live with me and be my love / words by C. Marlowe. - S.l.: s.n., no date., Hatton, John L. (Box 24, Folder 142)
    - Ave Maria. - Boston: Carl Prüfer, c1869., Hauptmann, Moritz, 1792-1868 (Box 24, Folder 142)
    - The marv'lous work. - Boston: Ditson & Company, no date., Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809 (Box 24, Folder 142)
    - The Lord is my light: a full anthem for four voices, with ad libitum accompaniment. - London: Novello, Ever & Company, no date., Hiles, Henry (Box 24, Folder 142)
    - I will wash my hands in innocency O Lord: anthem: for a tenor voice with chorus. - London: London Sacred Music Warehouse, J. Alfred Novello, no date., Hopkins, Edward J.; 1 score 3 parts. (Box 24, Folder 142)
    - Easter flowers are blooming bright. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, c1886., Howard, A.P. (Box 24, Folder 143)
    - [Hymns] S.l.: s.n., no date (Box 24, Folder 143)
      Incomplete, pp. 5-90 only.
    - Serenata. - New York: Edward Schuberth, c1881., Jonas, Ernst (Box 24, Folder 144)
    - 36 violin studies. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, no date., Kayser, H.E. (Box 24, Folder 144)
    - Milkmaid's marriage song / words by Alice Cary. - Boston: White, Smith & Perry, c1869., Keller, M. (Box 24, Folder 144)
    - Alladin: a Chinese suite for orchestra. - New York: G. Schirmer, c1915., Kelley, Edgar Stillman, 1857-1944 (Box 24, Folder 144)
    - O Lord, my God. - New York: G. Schirmer, c1890., Klein, B. Cecil (Box 24, Folder 145)
    - The song of spring: Frühlingslied. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, no date. (Box 24, Folder 145)
      Creator unknown, possibly Klingemann (firstname unknown).
    - O, for the wings of a dove. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, c1871., Knight, J.S. (Box 24, Folder 145)
    - Te deum. - New York: G. Schirmer, c1866., Kotzschmar, Hermann (Box 24, Folder 145)
    - Salve regina. - Boston: Carl Prüfer, c1874., Krawutschke, Robert (Box 24, Folder 145)
    - Oh my love he is a saileur: song. - New York: William Hall & Son, c1857. (Box 24, Folder 146)
      Words by Chas. M. Walcot.
      Creator unknown, possibly La Manna (firstname unknown).
    - Valse fantastique...: op. 6., Lambord, Benjamin; 8 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 24, Folder 146)
      Holograph signed (?), in ink.
      "Copyright, 1905, by the WA-Wan Press" - p. 1.
    - The cows are in the corn: encore song. - Boston: White, Smith and Company, c1878., Leslie, Herbert (Box 24, Folder 146)
    - The tale of the bell: a cantata / poem by Frederick H. Martens. - New York: J. Fischer & Brothers, C1917., Lester, William (Box 24, Folder 146)
    - Far from my thoughts, vain world, be gone: (inscribed to Mrs. Emma G. Stow)., Lippitt, F.J. (Box 24, Folder 146)
    - The golden threshold / words by Edward Oxenford. - [Boston]: Oliver Ditson, c1901., Löhr, Frederic N. (Box 24, Folder 146)
    - Lyrics of the red-man. - Wa-Wan Press: Newton Center, Mass., 1903., Loomis, Harvey Worthington (Box 24, Folder 146)
    - Una notte a Venezia...: duettino. - New York: G. Schirmer, c1871., Lucantoni, G. (Box 24, Folder 146)
    - Marionetten: sechs kleine Clavier-Stücke ... op. 38. - Breslau: Julius Hainauer, c1888., MacDowell, Edward, 1860-1908 (Box 24, Folder 147)
    - The beating of my own heart. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, c1858., Macfarren, G.A. (Box 24, Folder 147)
      Words by R. Moulton Milnes.
    - The song of home ... / words by George F. Morris. - New York Wm. Hall & Son, c1850., Maeder, J. Gaspard (Box 24, Folder 147)
    - Arise! Shine! For Thy light is come: anthem for Christmas. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, no date., Maker, F.C. (Box 24, Folder 147)
    - How beautiful on the mountains. - Boston: Arthur P. Schmidt, c1884., Marston, G.W. (Box 24, Folder 147)
    - Whoso dwelleth under the defence of the most high: evening anthem. - London: Novello Ewer and Company, no date., Martin, George C. (Box 24, Folder 147)
    - Non è ver. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, c1868., Mattei, Tito (Box 24, Folder 147)
    - Greeting / [words by] J. Von Eichendorff. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, no date., Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847 (Box 24, Folder 148)
    - Hear my prayer: hymn for soprano and chorus. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, no date., Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847 (Box 24, Folder 148)
    - Jesus be Thou ever near us. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, c1865., Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847 (Box 24, Folder 148)
    - Quartetto: O come every one. - Boston: E.H. Wade, no date., Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847 (Box 24, Folder 148)
    - Cavatina from Robert Le Diable: with English, French, German and Italian words. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, no date., Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864 (Box 24, Folder 149)
    - The hermit's prophecy. - New York: Atwill, c1847., Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864 (Box 24, Folder 149)
    - Gracious spirit: solo soprano and chorus. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, c1854., Minè, A. [i.e., Miné, A.] (Box 24, Folder 149)
    - Keltische Volkslieder. - Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, no date., Möller, Heinrich (Box 24, Folder 150)
    - The gobbler: turkey trot. - Boston: Boston Music Co., c1912., Monroe, Joe (Box 24, Folder 151)
    - Awake, awake, the day dawns: Easter carol / words by N.H.W. - New York: Wm. A. Pond, c1883., Mosenthal, Joseph (Box 25, Folder 152)
    - Te deum. - New York: William A. Pond, c1866., Mosenthal, Joseph (Box 25, Folder 152)
      Eight copies.
    - La ci darem là mano: duetto. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, no date., Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791 (Box 25, Folder 152)
    - Mammy, how I miss you. - New York: The Bandanna Publ. Company, c1909., Murphy, Janette Robinson (Box 25, Folder 152)
    - De Profundis: sacred solo; for alto or baritone. - Brooklyn: A.G. Slade, c1879., Navarro, Rafael (Box 25, Folder 154)
    - The forest queen / the words by Ch. Jefferys. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, no date., Nelson, S. (Box 25, Folder 154)
    - Ukolébavka: Wiegenlied. - Prague: Fr. A. Urbánek, no date., Nesvera, Jos. (Box 25, Folder 154)
    - Hope. - New York: C.H. Ditson, c1883., O'Connor, William P. (Box 25, Folder 155)
    - Jubilate. - S.l.: s.n., c1879 by Geo. D. Newhall., Osborn, E.F. (Box 25, Folder 155)
    - O God! Thou art my God / words selected from the Psalms of David. - New York: C.H. Ditson, no date., Petri, J.F. (Box 25, Folder 156)
    - Jesus, I my cross have taken. - [Boston]: Oliver Ditson, c1890., Reay, Samuel (Box 25, Folder 156)
    - Through another year / words by Rev. Alfred Taylor. - Boston: Louis H. Ross, c1887., Rising, J.A. (Box 25, Folder 156)
    - Cast thy bread upon the waters: quartette: for mixed voices. - Boston: White, Smith & Company, c1883. (Box 25, Folder 156)
      Creator unknown, possibly Roeckel (firstname unknown).
    - The honeymoon march. - New York: Jos. W. Stern, c1894., Rosey, George (Box 25, Folder 156)
    - Una voce poco fa. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, no date., Rossini, Gioacchino (Box 25, Folder 156)
    - Robin Ruff. - New York: Wm. A. Pond, c1843., Russell, Henry (Box 25, Folder 156)
    - The bridesmaids' duet: from the opera of "Maria Padilla." - Boston: Oliver Ditson, no date, Ryan, Desmond (Box 25, Folder 156)
    - Sacred Selection No. 1 -[Boston: W.H. Cundy], c1888. (Box 25, Folder 158)
    - Quatuor. - Paris: Durand & Schoenewerk, no date., Saint-Saens, Camille (Box 25, Folder 159)
    - Musikalische Gedenkblätter: für Streich Quartett. - Braunschweig: Henry Litolff's Verlag, no date., Schaper, Gustav (Box 25, Folder 160)
    - Easter anthem: Christ our Passover. - New York: G. Schirmer, c1884., Schilling, Fred (Box 25, Folder 160)
    - Serenade. - New York: G. Schirmer, no date., Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828; 1 score - 2 violin parts. (Box 25, Folder 160)
    - Hark! What mean those holy voices. - New York: G. Schirmer, c1868., Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 (Box 25, Folder 160)
    - Granados: Spanish dance / arr. by S. Seiniger. - Boston: Carl F. Ludwig, 1925., Seiniger, S. (Box 25, Folder 161)
      2 violin parts, manuscript (copy).
    - Five songs / the poems by James Russell Lowell. - Newton Center, Mass.: Wa-Wan Press, c1909., Shepherd, Arthur (Box 25, Folder 161)
    - Lord, what offering shall we bring. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, c1884., Silcher, Friedrich (Box 25, Folder 162)
    - As pants the hart: for soprano solo & quartette / arranged by M.F.H. Smith. - Detroit: C.J. Whitney, c1869., Smith, M.F.H. (Box 25, Folder 162)
    - Neuf petits morceaux: pour piano. - Paris: Léon Grus, no date., Stow, G.G. (Box 25, Folder 163)
    - The Lord is my Shepherd. - Boston: G.D. Russell, c1869., Strachauer, Hermann (Box 25, Folder 164)
    - One heart, one soul: polka mazurka. - [Boston: W.H. Cundy], c1885., Strauss, Johann (Box 25, Folder 165)
    - Father keep us in Thy care / words by B.F. Hodges; D.F. Hodges arranged from "The lost chord." - Boston: White, Smith & Company, c1881., Sullivan, Arthur, 1842-1900 (Box 25, Folder 166)
    - O hush thee, my babie / words by Sir Walter Scott. - Boston Oliver Ditson, no date., Sullivan, Arthur, 1842-1900 (Box 25, Folder 166)
    - Onward, Christian soldiers / [words by] S. Baring Gold. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, no date., Sullivan, Arthur, 1842-1900 (Box 25, Folder 166)
      Fifteen copies.
    - Say, watchman, what of the night?: eight-part chorus. - Boston: Ditson & Company, no date., Sullivan, Arthur, 1842-1900 (Box 25, Folder 166)
      Five copies, 4 copies with changes (manuscript in ink) pasted on.
    - I Fjol gjaett's Gjeitinn: norwegische Volksmelodie. - Leipzig: E.W. Fritzsch, no date., Svendsen, Johan S. (Johan Severin), 1840-1911 (Box 25, Folder 166)
      String parts.
    - Jesus calls us / adapted by W.M. Richardson. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, c1882. (Box 25, Folder 167)
      Creator unknown, possibly Sydenham (firstname unknown).
    - Souvenir de Florence: sextuor. - Hamburg; Leipzig: D. Rahter, no date., Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893 (Box 22)
      Bound volume.
    - God be merciful. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, c1862., Thomas, J.R. (Box 26, Folder 168)
      Nine copies.
    - O be joyful in the Lord. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, c1862., Thomas, J.R. (Box 26, Folder 169)
    - Praise the Lord. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, c1862., Thomas, J.R. (Box 26, Folder 170)
    - Te deum. - New York: Wm. Hall & Son, c1859., Thomas, J.R. (Box 26, Folder 171)
    - Stars of the summer night / words by Longfellow. - Philadelphia: Wm. H. Boner, no date., Tours, Berthold (Box 26, Folder 172)
    - Dancing in the barn: Schottisch / melody by Tom Turner and Ed. W. Orrin; arranged by Chas. E. Pratt. - New York: T.B. Harms & Francis, Day & Hunter, c1878., Turner, Tom (Box 26, Folder 172)
    - Parigi o cara. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, c1858?, Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901 (Box 26, Folder 172)
    - La queja. - Nueva York: En los Principales Almacenes de Musica, c1865., Vilanova, Ranieri (Box 26, Folder 172)
    - The king's birthday march. - S.l.: s.n., c1883 by Jean White (Ball-room orchestra No. 11, Vol. II)., Wagner, A. (Box 25, Folder 173)
    - Eine Faust-ouverture: Klavierauszug zu vier Händen. - Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, no date., Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883 (Box 26, Folder 174)
    - Lohengrin...: with Italian, German, and English words ... / edited by Arthur Sullivan and J. Pittman. - London: Boosey and Company, no date, Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883 (Box 26, Folder 174)
    - Love scene: Lohengrin... / arr. by Benj. Cutter. - Boston: Jean White, c1889., Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883 (Box 26, Folder 175)
    - [Master-singers of Nuremberg. Libretto. English] Master-singers of Nuremberg / rendered into English by H. and F. Darder. - Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1882., Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883 (Box 26, Folder 175)
    - [Das Rheingold. Libretto. German & English] - Mainz: Verlag von B. Schott's Söhne, 1882., Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883 (Box 26, Folder 175)
    - Die Walküre... / vollständiger Klavierauszug erleichterte Bearbeitung von F. Kleinmichel. - Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, no date., Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883 (Box 26, Folder 176)
    - The winds that waft my sighs to thee / words by H.W. Challis. - New York: William Hall & Son, c1856., Wallace, W. Vincent (Box 26, Folder 177)
    - Te deum laudamus. - Boston: William H. Gerrish, c1887., Warren, John C. (Box 26, Folder 177)
    - Turnham Toll / words by Fred. E. Weatherly. - Boston: Thompson & Odell, no date., Wellings, Milton (Box 26, Folder 177)
    - The wilderness. - London: Hall, Virtue & Company, no date., Wesley, Samuel Sebastian (Box 26, Folder 178)
    - Simply to Thy cross I cling. - Cleveland: S. Brainard, c1870., West, William (Box 26, Folder 178)
    - Ronde d'amour. - Boston: Oliver Ditson, c1908., Westerhout, Niccolo van (Box 26, Folder 178)
    - Wreath of school songs... - Boston: Benjamin B. Mussey, 1848., White, Edward L. (Box 26, Folder 179)
    - Song, [White, Elsie Fellows] (Box 26, Folder 179)
      - Song, 1 score ([9] p.); 34 cm.
        For voice, violin obbligato, and piano.
      - Song, 1 score (9 p.); 34 cm.
    - Miscellaneous unidentified loose sheets, (ca. 150 p.). (Box 26, Folder 180)
- Correspondence, 1858-1980; Series III; 4.6' (11 boxes)
  A. From Gilbert: 1. To wife and family. 2. To others (arranged chronologically).
  B. To Gilbert: 1. From wife and family (arranged chronologically). 2. From others (arranged alphabetically).
  C. Between Mrs. Gilbert and Others: 1. From Mrs. Gilbert. 2. To Mrs. Gilbert (arranged alphabetically).
  D. Between Isolde Therese Gilbert Horton and Others (arranged chronologically).
  E. Between Family (arranged chronologically).
  F. Between Family and Others (arranged chronologically).
  G. Re Gilbert's Collaboration with Edward S. Curtis (arranged chronologically).
  H. Re New Music Society of America (aArranged chronologically).
  I. Miscellaneous (arranged alphabetically and chronologically).
  Envelopes with notes have been kept and enclosures are indicated in the register. Cross-references have been made between individuals and corporate bodies.
  - Correspondence - From Gilbert, III.A
    - To wife and family, III.A.1
      - To wife (Helen Kalischer Gilbert), 1906-1925; 51 items. (Box 28, Folder 1-3)
      - To Parents, 1888-1924; 113 items. (Box 28, Folder 4-11)
      - To Daughters, 1895-1927; 4 items. (Box 28, Folder 12)
        (Isolde Therese Gilbert Horton and Elizabeth Yolande Gilbert Koloff)
      - To Others, no date; 2 items. (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - To Others, III.A.2
      - Mostly copies of typed letters and drafts., 1891-1928; ca. 389 items. (Box 29, Folder 13-29)
        Includes letters to: Atherton, Baker, Bartik, Bodanzky, Borofsky, Breil, Clifton, Diaghileff, Donovan, Downes, Engel, Farwell, Gatti-Casazza, Gilman, Gliere, Gray, Gruenberg, Halle, Hammerstein, Hare, Harmati, Harty, Hill, Ives, Jacobi, Juilliard, Kahn, Koussevitzky, La Follette, MacDowell (Marian), Mason, Moe, Monteux, Muck, Narodny, Naumberg, Rabaud, Ranck, Reiner, Rockefeller, Röder, Saerchinger, Smallens, Sonneck, Spalding, Tuthill, Wood, and Ziegler.
        See also: III. MUSICAL GAMES.
  - Correspondence - To Gilbert, III.B
    - From wife and family, III.B.1
      - From wife, 1904-1912; 14 items. (Box 30, Folder 30)
      - From family, 1881-1926; 61 items. (Box 30, Folder 31-33)
    - From others, III.B.2
      - A.D. Beach Company, 1918 Jun 21 (Box 30, Folder 34)
      - A.N. Marquis & Company, 1907 May 16 (Box 30, Folder 34)
      - Alb-? Arthur, 1908 Aug 20 (Box 30, Folder 34)
      - Allen, Hiram, 1899 Jul 12 (Box 30, Folder 34)
      - Alloo, Cecil and Modeste, no date (Box 30, Folder 34)
      - Altschule, Jacob, 1925 Oct 3 (Box 30, Folder 34)
      - American Book Company, 1915 Oct (Box 30, Folder 34)
      - American Express Company, 1918 Sep 16 (Box 30, Folder 34)
      - American Grand Opera Company, 1926 Jun 2 (Box 30, Folder 34)
      - American Indian Memorial Film, 1921 Aug 29 (Box 30, Folder 34)
      - American Institute of Patentees, 1927 Sep 16 (Box 30, Folder 34)
        Enclosures.
      - American Orchestral Society, 1924-1925; 10 or more items. (Box 30, Folder 35)
      - American Placer Corporation, 1912 Jun 25 (Box 30, Folder 35)
      - Antis, Greta, no date (Box 30, Folder 35)
      - Associated Authors and Compilers, 1913-1914 (Box 30, Folder 35)
        See also: Saerchinger, César.
      - Association for American Music, 1920 Jun-Aug (Box 30, Folder 35)
      - Atherton, Percy, 1913-1923 (Box 30, Folder 35)
        Enclosure.
      - Atlantic Monthly, 1921 Sep 27 (Box 30, Folder 35)
      - Atlas Film Corporation, 1918 Jun 15 (Box 30, Folder 35)
      - Austin, ?, 1911 Oct 2 (Box 30, Folder 35)
      - Avery, Helen Walters, 1889-1891; 10 or more items. (Box 30, Folder 36)
      - Bahn, B., 1918 May 7 (Box 30, Folder 37)
      - Baker, George P., 1918-1922 (Box 30, Folder 37)
      - Barlow, Howard, 1917-1925 (Box 30, Folder 37)
      - Barnhart, Harry, 1922 May 26 (Box 30, Folder 37)
      - Bartik, Ottakar, 1917 Jul-Sep; 10 or more items. (Box 30, Folder 38)
      - Bay State Road Trust, 1912 Dec 10 (Box 30, Folder 38)
      - Bayentz, Zabelle, 1924 Jul 31 (Box 30, Folder 38)
      - Ba-?, Richard, 1919 Apr (Box 30, Folder 38)
      - Becht, Helen M., 1926 Apr 19 (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - Beethoven-Zentenarfeier, ca. 1927 (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - Bentzon, Inger, 1927-1928 (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - Bickford, John C., 1926 Jun 8 (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - Biographical History of Massachusetts, 1918 Oct 10 (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - Birchard, Clarence, 1918-1928 (Box 30, Folder 39)
        See also: C.C. Birchard.
      - Bispham, David, 1906-1918 (Box 30, Folder 39)
        See also: VI. SCRAPBOOKS; Bertram Shapleigh.
      - Black Sand and Gold Recovery Company, 1912 Jul 1 (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - Blackwell, Lora Christie?, 1904 Jun 11 (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - Blodgett, Glen Walton, 1928 Jan 11 (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - Bodanzky, Artur, 1916 Nov 22 (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - Bohemians, 1914-1915 (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - Boni & Liveright Publishers, 1925 Nov 13 (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - Borofsky, Samuel H., 1924 Mar 8 (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - Bosanquet, Vivan, ca. 1927 Jul 2 (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - Boston Chamber of Commerce, 1919 Feb 26 (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - Boston Musicians' Protective Association, 1923 May 4 (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - Boston Post, 1926 Nov 6 (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - Boston Public Library, 1915-1924 (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - Boston Revere Beach & Lynn Railroad, 1924 Jun 6 (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - Boston Symphony Orchestra, 1919-1925 (Box 30, Folder 39)
        See also: Max Fiedler, Serge Koussevitzky, Pierre Monteux, and Henri Rabaud.
      - Breil, Joseph, 1920-1925 (Box 30, Folder 40)
        Musical sketch in pencil on back of 1 letter.
      - Bridgeport Land & Title Company, 1920 Dec 29 (Box 30, Folder 40)
      - Brothe, Eleanor M., no date (Box 30, Folder 40)
      - Brown, Abbie Farwell, 1909-1922 (Box 30, Folder 40)
      - Brown, Allen A., 1915 Apr 25 (Box 30, Folder 40)
      - Bullard, Charles, 1888 (Box 30, Folder 40)
      - Bunker, Clarence Alfred, 1922 (Box 30, Folder 40)
      - Burleigh, Louise, 1920 (Box 30, Folder 40)
      - B-?, J.M., 1907 (Box 30, Folder 40)
      - C.C. Birchard, 1907-1926; 10 or more items. (Box 30, Folder 41)
        See also: Clarence Birchard.
      - C.G. Röder, 1921-1922; 10 or more items. (Box 30, Folder 41)
      - C.W. Thompson & Company, 1909-1910 (Box 30, Folder 41)
      - Cable, George W., 1917-1920 (Box 30, Folder 41)
      - Cabot, Frederick P., 1926 Apr 3 (Box 30, Folder 41)
      - Cadman, Charles Wakefield, 1915-1917 (Box 30, Folder 41)
      - California Federation of Women's Clubs, 1918 Nov 11 (Box 30, Folder 41)
      - Cambridge Gas-Light Company, 1925 Mar 11 (Box 30, Folder 42)
      - Cambridge Public Library, 1917-1923 (Box 30, Folder 42)
      - Campbell, Stella Fenton, 1891-1895 (Box 30, Folder 42)
      - Carl Fischer, 1926 Mar 10 (Box 30, Folder 42)
      - Carpenter, John Alden, 1923 Feb 5 (Box 30, Folder 42)
      - Central Trust Company of Illinois, 1926 Sep 28 (Box 30, Folder 42)
      - Chadwick, George Whitefield, ca. 1925 Dec 25 (Box 30, Folder 43)
      - Chanler, Robert W., 1920-1922 (Box 30, Folder 43)
      - Chicago North Shore Festival Association, 1924 May 14 (Box 30, Folder 43)
      - Chicago Railways Association, 1926-1927 (Box 30, Folder 43)
      - Chicago Symphony Orchestra, 1919 Feb 27 (Box 30, Folder 43)
      - Clapp, Philip Greeley, 1917 Oct 9 (Box 30, Folder 43)
      - Clifton, Chalmers, 1916-1925 (Box 30, Folder 43)
      - Clifton, Elmer, 1922-1923 (Box 30, Folder 43)
        See also: Whaling Film Corporation.
      - Clifton, Wanda, 1923 Jan 30 (Box 30, Folder 43)
      - Cohen, Mary M.?, no date (Box 30, Folder 44)
      - Columbia Phonograph Company, 1926 Nov 29 (Box 30, Folder 44)
      - Community Arts Association, 1924 (Box 30, Folder 44)
      - Composers' Music Corporation, 1921-1925 (Box 30, Folder 44)
      - Connecticut. Probate Court., 1923 Aug 9 (Box 30, Folder 44)
      - Converse, Frederick S., 1915-1920 (Box 30, Folder 45)
      - Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague (Mrs. Frederic Shurtleff Coolidge), 1926-1927 (Box 30, Folder 46)
      - Coomaraswamy, Ananda, no date (Box 30, Folder 46)
      - Coon, Oscar, 1911-1920; 10 or more items. (Box 30, Folder 47)
      - Copeland, George, ca. 1917 Mar 6 (Box 30, Folder 47)
      - Cosmos Press, 1917 Dec 26 (Box 30, Folder 47)
      - Current Literature Publishing Company, 1918 Oct 14 (Box 30, Folder 47)
        See also: Saerchinger, César
      - Current Opinion, 1917 Jul 24 (Box 30, Folder 47)
      - Curtis, Edward S.
        See: G. Re Gilbert's Collaboration with Edward S. Curtis
      - Damrosch, Walter, 1913 Feb 8 (Box 31, Folder 48)
      - Dane, Ernest B., 1924 Apr 18 (Box 31, Folder 48)
      - Dann, Hollis, 1914 (Box 31, Folder 48)
      - Darrell, Robert Donaldson, 1926 Sep 10 (Box 31, Folder 48)
      - De Graff, Louise, no date (Box 31, Folder 48)
      - Decker, Phelps, no date (Box 31, Folder 48)
      - Dennett, J.V., 1921 Jun 7 (Box 31, Folder 48)
      - Denton, Sherman F., 1900-1923 (Box 31, Folder 48)
      - Denton Brothers, 1899 Jun 9 (Box 31, Folder 48)
      - Deutsch, Babette, 1920 Jun 25 (Box 31, Folder 48)
      - Downes, Olin, 1916-1927; 10 or more items. (Box 31, Folder 49-50)
      - Dunham, Glendilia M., 1891-1899 (Box 31, Folder 51)
      - Dunlop. William, 1919 May 19 (Box 31, Folder 51)
      - Dunn, James P., 1919 May 20 (Box 31, Folder 51)
      - Dykema, P.W., 1928 Apr 12 (Box 31, Folder 51)
      - D., D., no year Sep 29 (Box 31, Folder 51)
      - Eastman, George, 1923 Apr 3 (Box 31, Folder 52)
      - Eastman School of Music, 1928 May 4 (Box 31, Folder 52)
        See also: A.M. See.
      - Edson, Charles Farwell, 1918-1925 (Box 31, Folder 52)
      - Eliot, Charles W., 1904 Aug 16 (Box 31, Folder 52)
      - Emery, George W., ca. 1894 Mar 16 (Box 31, Folder 52)
      - Emery, M.M., 1916-1927 (Box 31, Folder 52)
      - Engel, Carl, 1921-1927 (Box 31, Folder 52)
        See also: Library of Congress.
      - Etude Music Magazine, 1924-1925 (Box 31, Folder 52)